Preparing visual assets for collage
is a tedious and time-consuming process.
We introduce Collaposer, a tool that transforms photo collections
into visual assets for storytelling with collages.
Let's follow Lucas, a 2D motion designer,
as he creates a collage animation with the help of Collaposer.
Lucas begins with a folder of images
as he envisions a giant cat living in the countryside.
He browses through the album and types a story description.
A big cat is resting in a landscape under a blue sky with some clouds,
featuring a huge moon.
A man in white and red clothing is jumping on its back,
while a woman is lying there as well.
In the foreground, there are also some trees and plants.
It contains fixed elements directly related to the narrative,
while it also contains abstract words that
indirectly suggest additional visual elements related to the story.
In the backend, Collaposer extracts and clusters
visual elements from the photo collection based on the description.
After clustering,
character assets are segmented into body parts
with key points estimated for each section,
in preparation for articulated animation and deformation.
When the preparation of visual assets is completed,
the system interface transitions to the layer panel.
On the canvas view,
clustered elements are presented together.
The elements are resized based on selection criteria
to improve visibility and make them easier to select.
In the tree view
visual elements appear as leaf nodes
in a structured layer hierarchy,
providing an organized overview.
Lucas grasps an overview of the visual assets
and quickly identifies visual elements that catch his interest.
He interacts with both views to select desired elements
and arrange them into a static collage.
Lucas is satisfied with the scene and clicks export to obtain
two JSON files.
One that records the visual assets prepared by the system
and another that captures the final collage
information on the canvas,
along with a screenshot.
He runs an Extendscript script.
These files are read as clustered layers in Adobe After Effects.
Character layers are replaced by a set of body parts
with joint points serving as rotation centers.
Lucas adds a paper texture to the background
and adjusts the color
to match the desired tone of the composition.
He then animates the collages especially for characters,
as the separated body parts and body key points
allow for shape deformation and articulated animation.
Here are some animated collages
created with the output of Collaposer.